<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-12-13T14:17:24-05:00</updated><id>https://tinkerjae.xyz//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tinker Jae!</title><subtitle>Hi! Welcome to my new site! This website exists as my personal home on the internet where I can post about my daily life, projects, hobbies, poetry, and cool stuff I&apos;ve found on the internet.</subtitle><author><name>Jae</name></author><entry><title type="html">My position on studying</title><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/24/studying.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My position on studying" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/24/studying</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/24/studying.html"><![CDATA[<p>A mini-essay on studying that I didn’t want rotting in my journal.</p>

<p>So I think for a while I’ve rejected ideas about school and how to view it. I’ve seen the way people think about school as either something they enjoy doing or something they ‘have to do’ as really depressing for the latter option.</p>

<p>I’ve always had a priority for intrinsic motivation or ‘1st cause motivation.’ These are things you do simply because you like doing them. The way activities beget themselves is good, not morally or anything but the more you do it, the more you enjoy it. That’s how I see video games and working out. I don’t really think about ‘Oh I’m resting a good amount’ or ‘I’m hitting peak performance in this workout,’ I just do it and enjoy it.</p>

<p>This semester in college I took the only economics course I need to take for my degree, econ 1000. This course was mostly a rehash of concepts my high school economics class covered, but went into more detail on some things. This course reinvigorated my perceptions on extrinsic or ‘2nd cause’ motivation. ‘You want x thing, do y for me,’ is the way it works. Jobs for example are majority 2nd cause motivators, you go to work so you can make money to do other things.</p>

<p>For as far back as I can remember I’ve been trying to do things off 1st cause motivation alone. In college I’ve hit a wall so many times I’ve started imprint myself on it’s face. Repeatedly the work required by my courses has exceeded my 1st cause motivation. No matter how hard I try to care, I cannot for the life of me care about studying the little individual things that are required by an engineering bachelors program.</p>

<p>I recently have had a minor breakthrough in this wall. ‘Not everything you do is going to be fun.’ Obvious, to most people probably, but to me it’s important. All my life I’ve had the belief that you should be intrinsically motivated to do as many things as you can. For the first time in my life it feels like I can stop trying to care, stop trying to make it fun, stop trying to make it apart of who I am just to do the task.</p>

<p>The energy I’ve had to spend to do the most menial tasks has been ridiculous and now it feels like I can stop pretending. I no longer have to make myself enjoy the stuff I don’t enjoy. I’m freer now than I was 30 minutes ago before I wrote this because I don’t have to pretend to be someone I’m not.</p>

<p>I don’t care about school, not really. I care about learning, that’s who I am, but I am not a studier. That’s okay though, I don’t have to craft myself into ‘someone who enjoys studying,’ I can just do it and be as bad as I need to be in order to get it done. An anchor has lifted from my chest and I feel relieved.</p>

<p>I got into my engineering program because of two reasons. One, my partner was going to break up with me if I didn’t do it. Two, I want to learn engineering. I don’t care about getting a job with my degree, I don’t care about making a lot of money. I just wanted to learn firsthand what the skills were in order to do engineering so I can design, build, &amp; test things. If you were me, you would assume that would be intrinsic motivation to study, but you would be wrong.</p>

<p>Studying and coursework are not the same thing as what I want to do. I don’t want to complete tasks given by professors, I want to have knowledge and skill and be able to work with my hands as well as my mind. That is not the same as studying. However, I do have to study in order to have the knowledge and skill I desire. To me, studying is a means to an end, not the end itself. Even though I enjoy it sometimes, I will find ways to bypass it if I can. That means to me, I must study as it’s the only option, and I don’t have to force myself to enjoy it. I just have to study as long as it means I can pursue the knowledge and skills I desire. That in a way, is comforting.</p>

<p>In summary, I only need to study as much as I am required. Studying is a choice I make because it is a grueling process but worth the fruits it bears. I don’t have to like it, I just have to stick with it enough to get what I need out of it. Studying is the time and effort that it costs in order to purchase new skills from the universe. It is a price I will haggle with when possible, but it is almost always a price I’m willing to pay even if I’d rather it not be paid at all.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jae</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="school" /><category term="essay" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A mini-essay on studying that I didn’t want rotting in my journal.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Journey with School</title><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/06/journey-with-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Journey with School" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/06/journey-with-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/06/journey-with-school.html"><![CDATA[<p>How ya going?</p>

<p>Still on my silly journey to be happy. I’ve decided I want to post on the internet about my journey with school as someone who’s not super mega rich, and also neurodivergent. If you don’t know, I’ve got ADHD, it makes school and life really hard so I use lots of tools. I have an <a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian</a> vault with over 1300 files in it, along with several journals. I meditate, I exercise, I sleep well, etc. I’ve tried using a lot of natural methods to help curb the negative symptoms of ADHD, but it’s not enough. I’m currently pursuing an ADHD diagnosis as a 20 year old adult. I am male so my chances are much higher of the doctor taking me seriously, but it’s never a good experience to have the fate of your future in the neurotypical world determined by someone who can dismiss your concerns, especially for females. Nonetheless, I’m sure it’ll go well, and if it won’t I will keep on moving. Funny isn’t it, one thing I think my ADHD has given me is the ability to keep trying, even though it doesn’t work 99.9999% of the time.</p>

<p>But yeah as of right now I’ve just received news that my most recent Calculus 2 test flopped. 53/100, though I did score a 94/100 on the one before that so not all hope is lost. I feel I just didn’t prepare properly, I’ll try something different for the next test and here it is so far. I’m journaling and publishing my journey with school on the internet.</p>

<p>I’m also trying to prioritize happiness for myself. Right now it seems that publishing:</p>

<ol>
  <li>My journey with school.</li>
  <li>Me doing/making more projects</li>
  <li>And my learning of new skills.</li>
</ol>

<p>is what makes me happy. Until this next test I’m going to try to prioritize treating school as an enjoyable experience. I want to enjoy school, and it helps that if I don’t enjoy it I act like a kid being fed vegetables. I’m serious about that too, it’s like my body rejects anything if I try too hard to like it or be good at it. For more on that phenomena look into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executive_dysfunction">executive dysfunction</a>.</p>

<p>My current idea is to treat school as a hobby, to try to enjoy it more than anything. And when I feel I’m done, I’m done. Doesn’t matter if there’s an assignment, I’d rather sacrifice a little short term productivity, for long term continuation of something I want to do. Today I’m going to rep out some Calc 2 Homework, as well as a MATLAB Assignment. But yeah, that’s all for today, see ya later!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jae</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="school" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How ya going?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happiness, Absurdism, &amp;amp; Love</title><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/04/happiness-absurdism-love.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happiness, Absurdism, &amp;amp; Love" /><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/04/happiness-absurdism-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/03/04/happiness-absurdism-love.html"><![CDATA[<p>An essay on happiness, absurdism, and love.</p>

<p>This is gonna be kind of a <del>two</del> three part essay. We’ve got part one that’s gonna be on happiness and our journey/where we wanna go next. Then part two which is about absurdism. Then part three which is about a solution to the absurd. It ended up being way bigger than intended and probably good enough to publish.</p>
<h1 id="part-one-happiness">Part One: Happiness</h1>
<p>So we’ve recently started abandoning our notions of choosing to be effective. It wasn’t working for us. Pursuing happiness takes care of us being you know, happy. It also makes us more effective at doing stuff in our life. That’s good. I want to know where we want to go next.</p>

<p>I’ll touch on this more later, but I was watching <a href="https://youtu.be/OkzkQM-k66U?si=WlMz3lImwOf8ilD3">this video essay</a>, and there was a point on how artists and creatives are encouraged to be ambitious. Ambition is like a staircase, the only point is the reach the top. The answer the video essay was providing to escape the trap of ambition, is to enjoy the journey. Enjoy and “be content with the step you’re currently on”, he said.</p>

<p>That got me thinking about the Myth of Sisyphus. Our man Sisyphus does a lot of crazy shit, gets punished by the gods, and has to roll a boulder up a hill only for it to fall back down for all of eternity. Crazy story yeah? Well Albert Camus certainly thought so, when he wrote “The Myth of Sisyphus” and published it in 1942. I won’t go too deep into it, as I only know the cliff notes, but I’ve been tempted to read it more as of late. The staircase and the boulder are one and the same.</p>

<p>This got me thinking about my own philosophy, how do I define the absurd, and how do we (or I) deal with it? But before we jump into that, I wanted to make a rough snapshot of what I think would make me happy right now.</p>

<p>The general summary is that the absurd is different for different people, and people will deal with it differently depending on different factors. For me it seems that holding two contradictory viewpoints and finding happiness on that line in the middle between the two, makes me the most happy. Not believing in any capital G god, but still praying. Realizing that the institution of school is fucked up, but still learning from it anyways. Knowing that my life doesn’t matter but learning and loving and living, both because of that and in spite of that.</p>

<p>You confused yet? Well there’s more in part two.</p>
<h1 id="part-two-absurdism">Part Two: Absurdism</h1>
<p>I made a lot of voice notes in a group chat between 2 of my close friends and I. The summary was that, I define the absurd to be the contradiction of us living in a universe that is both irrational, chaotic, and almost unreal in it’s brief and sudden endings, while also recognizing that in some ways the universe must have order, it must be rational. This reflects onto us, we are creatures in search for meaning, that can find meaning in things, but also shouldn’t be able to? If that doesn’t make sense, I’ll try and elaborate.</p>

<p>You step outside on a warm spring afternoon, the sky is an almost perfect but random cacophony of clouds and colors. The birds are singing, the wind is blowing. You somehow feel both ultimately free, and peacefully grounded. Your dog, who you love very much, steps outside to accompany you. In this moment of pure bliss, he takes a shit on your porch, and then waltz’s back inside like nothing just happened.</p>

<p>That is the absurd in my eyes. It’s the contradiction of things in this world that are somehow both so full of meaning and order, but also not. Things are rational and make sense, until they don’t. We are beings of both chaos and order, rationality, and irrationality. We’re both a reflection of the world we live in, and something completely separate from it.</p>

<p>Another way I think of it, is that we are creatures able to genuinely find meaning in things, but also able to rationally deduce that there is no inherent meaning. There cannot be inherent meaning due to the nature of things, but there is, it’s right there! You see it in the birds, the trees, the smiles on peoples faces. There is meaning, but there also can’t be. That’s a contradiction both within, and outside of ourselves. I mean that to say that we can see this contradiction in the outside world, but also within our inner thoughts.</p>

<h1 id="part-three-breakthrough">Part Three: Breakthrough</h1>
<p>My head is starting to hurt, let’s pivot a little, shall we? We’re able to find meaning in things, but rationally shouldn’t be able to, but it does work. So then what are we supposed to do?</p>

<p>My answer is as I stated earlier, we need to do both. We have a problem that we can’t have our cake and eat it too, but why not bake two cakes? Can we hold both the opinion that true objective meaning is impossible in this world, and still be able to have meaning somehow? I think that we can.</p>

<p>This is gonna be tough to pull off, but let’s pretend for a second that we can do it. What then? What can we do if there is a way for us to ride the line between meaning and meaninglessness? What should we do? It’s a big question to answer, and I don’t think I’m qualified to tell you what you should or shouldn’t do in this situation. I can tell you what I’m going to do though. I’m going to live.</p>

<p>I think Camus says something about being so free that even in a cage your very existence is an act of rebellion, I think I agree. I’m going to live, and prioritize my happiness. I will follow my whimsey where it takes me. And when life has me down, and my avenues for action have been exhausted, Amor fati. I will love my fate, and be so joyous in the most monotonous situations, because if I can be so free that even dreadful chains can’t break me, then I can never be truly imprisoned.</p>

<p>“But what about morals,” I hear a nagging voice say. Those are important yes, we often need something to guide us, a light to hold dear to, a guiding hand. But what then, when there can be no objective meaning, no truth? I think Kendrick Lamar says it best on ‘Auntie Diaries’:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I said, “Mr. Preacher man, should we love thy neighbor?
The laws of the land or the heart, what’s greater?
I recognize the study she was taught since birth
But that don’t justify the feelings that my cousin preserved”
The building was thinking out loud, bad angel
That’s when you looked at me and smiled, said, “Thank you”
The day I chose humanity over religion
The family got closer, it was all forgiven</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Love, love seems to be the key. If you want a more specific definition of what kind of love, I mean the kind described by bell hooks in her book ‘All About Love: New Visions.’ Love that encourages the “nurturing [of] one’s own, or another’s spiritual growth.” Even though there is no meaning objectively, we can still find nuggets of meaning in our lives. I personally have found it through different kinds of love, such as platonic, romantic, and familial. This also ties into the philosophy of Waymond Wang from EEAAO.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“I don’t know. The only thing I do know… is that we have to be kind. Please, be kind - especially when we don’t know what’s going on.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Even if morals and what we ought to do can be fuzzy, I think love and kindness can serve as a lighthouse in the foggy sea of nuanced moral theories. We should try and keep some good morals, but when all else fails, love and kindness are the beacons we need to guide us. That’s at least what I’ll be using to guide me.</p>
<h1 id="part-four-summary">Part Four: Summary</h1>
<p>More specifically, and finally. What’s going to make me happy? I think in regards to our topic of meaning and contradictions, me realizing that things are complicated, that we and the world are both rational and irrational, but embracing that contradiction, is what makes me happy. And with a confusing absurd theory on what the meaning of life is, love and kindness are there to act as guiding stars in my journey of life.</p>

<p>Choosing to live and exist as much as one can, constantly revolting from the mundane assassination of my spirit, and keeping love &amp; kindness as close friends. That is what will make me happy.</p>
<h1 id="final-notes-references--recommended-media">Final Notes, References, &amp; Recommended Media</h1>
<p>If this piece made you think more, or think differently about your life, then please consider sharing with someone who might benefit from reading this. I don’t like urging people to “like and subscribe” but I hope this can be of value to you and others you may know.</p>

<p>In the middle of writing this piece, I ended up going on a hike as a little date. It was fun, beautiful, and relieving with a beautiful waterfall at the end of our trail. Before driving home, I got hit in the eye with my boyfriends jacket zipper on accident. Just thought that was a funny example of the absurd in action.</p>

<p>If you enjoyed this piece, please consider indulging in any of the media I mentioned. I’ve provided some links to where you can learn more.</p>

<p>Thanks again for reading, have a good morning, good evening, or good night.</p>

<p><a href="https://youtu.be/OkzkQM-k66U?si=lbqwKIms_G0vJivl">How to Escape the Neoliberal Lie | Kendrick Lamar &amp; Whiplash</a>(YouTube)<br />
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Myth_of_Sisyphus">“The Myth of Sisyphus” by Albert Camus</a>(Wikipedia)<br />
<a href="https://philosophy.as.uky.edu/sites/default/files/The%20Absurd%20-%20Thomas%20Nagel.pdf">“The Absurd” by Thomas Nagel</a>(PDF)<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/pHXgp46Qskg?si=CklJh07hTZvlh3rE">Miguel’s DESTRUCTIVE Idea of “SPIDER-MAN”</a>(YouTube)<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/-vrhf1P9zwc?si=r6Va_c20FG7RtHRI">Kendrick Lamar - Auntie Diaries</a>(YouTube)<br />
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_About_Love:_New_Visions">“All About Love: New Visions” by bell hooks</a>(Wikipedia)<br />
<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6710474/">Everything Everywhere All at Once</a>(IMDb)<br /></p>

<p><a href="https://files.catbox.moe/k27b3r.pdf">PDF Download of this Document</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Jae</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="philosophy" /><category term="essay" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An essay on happiness, absurdism, and love.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">42%</title><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/resources/2025/02/26/forty-two-percent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="42%" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/resources/2025/02/26/forty-two-percent</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/resources/2025/02/26/forty-two-percent.html"><![CDATA[<p>A writing on rest.</p>

<p>I’ve been very burnt out as of late, it’s been pretty bad and I want it to get better. I’m trying really hard to keep my shit together but it ain’t easy. I found <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/cookiedoughmeagain/663232885726281728/youreastargirl-cookiedoughmeagain">this tumblr post</a> via pinterest and I thought I’d save it here for future safekeeping and share it with the internet while I’m at it.</p>

<p>The first big thing is this:
<img alt="Forty-Two_Percent_From_Burnout_Solve_Your_Stress_Cycle_By_Emily&amp;Amelia_Nagoski" src="https://files.catbox.moe/d4iqhq.jpg" width="500" /></p>

<p>You need a minimum of at least 42% rest, that is not a suggestion, that is a requirement. If that requirement isn’t met upfront it will come back to haunt you. I say this to mean, if you don’t treat yourself right the universe will force you to until it starts to kill you slowly then all at once.</p>

<p>This only further forces the point, that people can only do what they can do. If pushed to their limit they will struggle, and beyond that you will be crushed under your own weight. Not to be dramatic, but that’s not good.</p>

<p>So what does this mean for you or I? It means TAKE A GOD DAMN BREAK! There are too many self righteous people (me included) that will work till they fall apart and this I’m here to remind both you and myself that you have limits. Stretch them, sure, but breaking your limits breaks you, and not only is it not a good idea ethically, morally, or spiritually, but for the sake of efficiency there is no point to do it that way. Get comfortable with where you are, for even as you are, you are great.</p>

<p>Furthermore, what is rest? If we’re gonna do that let’s do it well enough. Well it’s many things, but it ain’t just sleep.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Sleep</li>
  <li>Meditation</li>
  <li>Meaningful conversation with someone you have a connection with</li>
  <li>Exercising</li>
  <li>Paying attention to your food, whether that’s shopping for it, cooking it or eating it</li>
  <li>Socialising</li>
  <li>Daydreaming</li>
  <li>Joy</li>
  <li>Whimsy</li>
</ul>

<p>These are all valid forms of rest. When getting your 42%, treat it like food, get a wide variety to cover your bases, and trust your gut.</p>

<p>TL:DR; Please rest, do so well, and take care of yourself. It’s not only good for the soul, but actually neccessary for your body and productivity as well. Now I’m gonna get to bed as it’s currently 9:45pm EST.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jae</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="resources" /><category term="vent" /><category term="essay" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A writing on rest.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’ve started martial arts!</title><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/02/25/martial-arts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’ve started martial arts!" /><published>2025-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/02/25/martial-arts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/02/25/martial-arts.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey! It hasn’t been that long suprisingly.</p>

<p>I recently visited my uni’s martial arts club. I had a ton of fun. I didn’t know what I was doing but I definitely enjoyed 90% of it, the other 10% was just neutral. It’s mainly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muay_Thai">Muay Thai</a> focused but they do a bit of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taekwondo">Taekwondo</a> as well. I don’t know much if anything about martial arts so I learned some of the basics. Jab, cross, teep, roundhouse, and I tried learning a hook kick and am just not there yet. I haven’t sparred yet but I’m very excited to. I took some vids of everyone sparring and won’t post them but once I do start sparring I’ll post it. Overall 10/10 for an introduction to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muay_Thai">the art of eight limbs</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jae</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="martial-arts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey! It hasn’t been that long suprisingly.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tabula Rasa</title><link href="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/02/19/tabula-rasa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tabula Rasa" /><published>2025-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/02/19/tabula-rasa</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tinkerjae.xyz//blog/2025/02/19/tabula-rasa.html"><![CDATA[<p>A fresh start.</p>

<p>Welcome all to my new website! This is my first official post, glad you’re reading it. I’m planning a lot of things for this site, so stay tuned. For now I thought I’d kill two birds with one stone. This website is currently what’s known as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tabula_rasa">tabula rasa</a> or blank slate. I don’t plan on adding much in terms of old content as that will stay on the <a href="https://tinkerjae.neocities.org/">old site</a> but there will be new stuff coming soon.</p>

<p>The next things I need to work on are:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Adding categories for posts and sectioning them off.</li>
  <li>Fleshing out the website by posting more stuff.</li>
  <li>Adding a more realized about page.</li>
  <li>Adding a more realized home page.</li>
  <li>Giving the old site a warning label that I’m moving to this url for good.</li>
</ol>

<p>That’s all for now, tata!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jae</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fresh start.]]></summary></entry></feed>